## Siva Kumar B

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

siva3062000@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/siva3062000 | siva3062000.github.io | github.com/siva3062000

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

A passionate software engineer with 2+ years of experience in frontend development looking to seek a position in an organization to utilize my programming, technical and communication skills as well as to contribute myself in achieving the goals of the organization and to gain experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

## SMK Fomra Institute of Technology, Anna University, India

Sep 2021

Bachelors of Engineering (BE) in Computer Science and Engineering

(CGPA: 8.19/10)

## KC Sankaralinga Nadar Hr. Sec. School, State Board of Tamil Nadu, India

April 2017

**HSC** in Computer Science

82%

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### LTIMindtree, Chennai, India

Oct 2021 - Present

Software Engineer | Frontend developer | React JS, Tailwind CSS, Gatsby JS, Contentful CMS, Jest

- Worked in 6+ projects for Retail and Consumer Goods (RCG) BU client.
- Created content model and entries in Contentful CMS.
- Wrote GraphQL query to fetch data for React Components.
- Developed ReactJS components, hooks and page templates.
- Styled components in a responsive way using Tailwind CSS in mobile first approach.
- Worked on React forms and form validations.
- Optimized page performance to improve google lighthouse performance score.
- Wrote unit testcases to achieve SonarCloud 80% quality standard.
- Worked on bug fixing.
- Added GA/GTM tags into the site.
- Prepared R2O documentation.

# **OWN PROJECTS**

### HobbyBook (siva3062000.github.io/storybook)

Dec 2023 - Present

StoryBook | Storybook, React JS, Tailwind CSS

- A Storybook Component Library Web App to practice front-end skills as a hobby
- Created many reusable react components.

### Portfolio (siva3062000.github.io)

Jan 2024 - Jan 2024

Static site | Next JS, React JS, Tailwind CSS

- A simple portfolio website to showcase skillsets.
- Achieved 100% Google Lighthouse Performance for Desktop and 90+% for Mobile.

### **SKILLS**

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3
- Frameworks and Libraries: React JS, Tailwind CSS, Next JS, Gatsby JS, Redux, GraphQL
- Others: Git and Github, GCP fundamentals
- · Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Communication, Teamwork, Adaptability

## **COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

React JS with Redux 201 Course at LTIMindtree.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Received Best Performer, Super Crew and A-Team awards at LTIMindtree.
- Secured 1<sup>st</sup> place in chess competition at college and 2<sup>nd</sup> place at school.

### **LANGUAGES**

- English
- Tamil